<resources>
    <string name="app_name">WomenSafetyAlertApplication</string>
    <string name="title_activity_sign_up">SignUpActivity</string>
    <!--
    This string is used for square devices and overridden by hello_world in
    values-round/strings.xml for round devices.
    -->
    <string name="hello_world">Hello Square World!</string>
    <string name="title_activity_home">Home</string>
    <string name="title_activity_maps">Map</string>

    <string name="nav_header_desc">Navigation header</string>
    <string name="menu_home">Home</string>
    <string name="menu_safetyTips">Women Safety Tips</string>
    <string name="menu_defenseTips">Defense Tips</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_close">Close Navigation</string>
    <string name="navigation_drawer_open">Open Navigation</string>
    <string name="title_activity_viewing_map">Map</string>

    <string-array name="SafetyTips">
        <item>ALWAYS BE AWARE
            While going through your day to day duties of work, kids, school run, dinner – all those fun life admin tasks that never stop, keep awareness top of mind. Regularly check on your home security and look for anything that’s out of place, don’t forget to arm your alarm when leaving in a rush, and always take note of your surroundings.
        </item>
        <item> TAKE SELF-DEFENSE TRAINING.
        It is important to evaluate the goals and practical usefulness of a women’s self-defense program before signing up.</item>
        <item>YOU HAVE A RIGHT TO FIGHT.
        Unfortunately, no matter how diligently we practice awareness and avoidance techniques, we may find ourselves in a physical confrontation.
            Whether or not you have self-defense training, and no matter what your age or physical condition, it is important to understand that you
            CAN and SHOULD defend yourself physically. You have both the moral and legal right to do so, even if the attacker is only threatening you
            and hasn’t struck first.
        </item>
        <item> AVOID A CAR-JACKING.
        Lock all doors and keep windows up when driving. Most car-jackings take place when vehicles are stopped at intersections. The criminals approach at a 45-degree angle (in the blind spot), and either pull you out of the driver’s seat or jump in the passenger’s seat.
        </item>
        <item> BE PREPARED WHEN YOU TRAVEL.
        Violent crimes against women happen in the best and worst hotels around the world. Predators may play the part of a hotel employee, push their way through an open or unlocked door, or obtain a pass key to the room. As with home safety, never open your door unless you are certain the person on the other side is legitimate, and always carry a door wedge with you when you travel. A wedge is often stronger than the door it secures.</item>
        <item> NEVER PULL OVER when someone points at your car, claiming that something is wrong. Suspects use this tactic to get you to open your window or get out of the car. Rather drive to the nearest garage or shop where you will be safe to have a look yourself or can ask for assistance
        </item>
        <item> Please trust and make good use of your ‘gut feel’ or ‘intuition’ or ‘sixth sense’ in each and every place and situation</item>
        <item>Make it a habit to read and notice these warning signs and go with your intuition to quickly retract yourself, move out or immediately get away from potentially unsafe situations</item>
        <item>While using 2 wheeler be sure to wear helmet at all times (especially at night). Don’t stop for any stranger</item>
        <item> In case you are in a sticky situation don’t be afraid to use anything in your hand to defend yourself

       Use keys, bottle even your purse to inflict damage to your attacker</item>

        <item> In case you feel you are being stalked or regularly followed, don’t keep it to yourself because what might be on lighter side now might become dangerous if not controlled

            a.       Seek help of friends and family

            b.      If need be approach police immediately</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="defenseTipsTitle">
        <item>Start by identifying the vulnerable places on the human body.</item>
        <item> Practice several of the simplest and most damaging moves.</item>
        <item>If grabbed from the front, get space and attack the forehead.</item>
        <item> Use simple escapes to free your hands.</item>
        <item> Attacking from the side.</item>
        <item>Attacking while cornered against a wall.</item>
    </string-array>

    <string-array name="defenseTipsBody">
        <item>The first one is to control the wrist and spread the fingers apart. Using both hands, grab the pinky and the ring in one hand and the middle and index finger in the other. With control of the hand, pull the fingers in opposite directions and bend the wrist backward.

In the second move, aim for your attacker’s throat with a fist or pointed fingers, specifically between the collarbones or into the Adam’s apple. Finally, the third move is the most universal: knee or punch the attacker in the groin and use the distraction to get away.</item>
        <item>If you have little room and can’t lift your hands, thrust your hands forward and make a fist in front of your pelvis to get a little room from your attacker. After that, headbutt your attacker in the nose and follow that with a knee attack to the groin.</item>
        <item>If your attacker grabs your wrist to control your hands from above, roll your wrist toward their thumb, up and through to break the grip. If your arm is underneath, you can also pull to throw the attacker off-balance.</item>
        <item>If you are grabbed from behind, bend back to try and attack the nose with the back of the leg. Even if you miss, that’s ok—your opponent will put one of his legs forward. From this position, bend down and grab the leg and try to pull it out from underneath him.</item>
        <item>If someone comes at you from the side, use elbow strikes to the face and groin. A well-placed strike to the side of the temple will also do a lot of damage and buy time.</item>
        <item>What you do here largely depends on their body language and your position relative to them. The main rule is: attack the most vulnerable position. If their arms are up, attack the armpits. If one of your arms is low and free, us it to attack the neck or jaw. If you’re pinned, attack with your head.</item>

    </string-array>


    <string name="permission"> Background Location is required for the core functionality of the program. Please go to permission of app from the setting button here and select ALLOW ALL THE TIME for location access.</string>
    <string name="smspermission"> SMS permission is required for the core functionality of the program. It is required for sending sms to your emergency contacts during emergency. Please go to permission of app below and select ALLOW ALL THE TIME.</string>

    <string name="permission_rationale">Location permission is needed for core functionality</string>
    <string name="permission_denied_explanation">Permission was denied, but is needed for core functionality.</string>
    <string name="settings">Settings</string>
    <string name="title_activity_friends_map">Map</string>
</resources>